(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-17T17:01:15.603306",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
みなさんこんにちは！ホロライブゲーマーズの常闇トワ様です！イェーイ！
Hello everyone! It's Tokoyami Towa-sama of Hololive Gamers! Yay!
もうとんでもないテンションで入ってきちゃったんですけど、まあ、はい……
I came in with an absurd amount of tension, but well, yeah...
さっきまでね、あの、今日来てくれるみんなと大笑いしてたんで
Just a while ago, I was laughing so hard with everyone who's coming today,
ありえないテンションで入ってきちゃいました。すみません！先にあやまっておきますけども、はい。
so I came in with impossible energy. Sorry! I'll apologize in advance, though, yeah.
で、はい、今日はなんと、えーみんなに重大発表があります！イェーイ！
And, yeah, today, amazingly, um, I have a big announcement for everyone! Yay!
でもね、その重大発表には、なんと魔力を集めて
But for that big announcement, apparently we have to gather magic power
トワの真の力を解放しなきゃいけないんです。え、トワ色？やば、ごめん。えー、そういうことになっているんですね。はい。
and unleash Towa's true power... Wait, Towa color? Yaba, sorry. Yeah.
ねえ、ちょっとみんなもこうやってるの？すごいだから、あっちも大笑いが、えー、そういうことになってるんです。はい。
Hey, are everyone doing this too? It's amazing, so over there they're laughing hard too, um, that's how it is. Yeah.
走ってく！えー、こちらのね、えー、トワ様重大発表でね、みんないっぱい呟いてくれたら嬉しいなと思います。応援してね！
Running! Um, for this, um, Towa-sama's big announcement, I'd be happy if everyone tweets a lot. Support me!
そして、まあ、もうあの何度も話し出しちゃってるんですけど、今日はゲストがいるので、そちらのゲストとね一緒に協力して魔力を集めていこうかなって思います。
And, well, as I've mentioned many times, we have a guest today, so I thought we could cooperate with that guest to gather magic power.
だって悪者だから。えー、ということで、早速呼んじゃいましょう！
Because after all, I'm a villain. Um, with that said, let's call them out right away!
みんなー！
Everyone!
ぺこちゃんが死にそう で
Peko-chan looks like she's gonna die.
死んでねえしぺこちゃん！ぺこちゃんが
I'm not dying, Peko-chan! Peko-chan is...
いや、違う。あの、さっきまでの配信のさ、ときに、前にさ、笑ってたね、トワを引きずらないように頑張ろうねって言ってたのに！
No, wait. Um, earlier during the stream, right before, we said 'Let's work hard not to drag Towa down with our laughter'!
トワ様、柔らかいところ……
Towa-sama, soft spots...
ぺこちゃん、それ過敏だよ！もうなんか全部じゃん！
Peko-chan, you're too sensitive! It's like everything!
ぺこちゃん結構あとから笑い来るタイプで
Towa-chan is the type who laughs a bit later,
そうだよ！みんなが一息ついたときにひとりでケラケラ笑ってるじゃん！
That's right! When everyone catches their breath, you're laughing all alone by yourself!
そうだよね、うん。
That's right, yeah.
はい、ということで、じゃあ自己紹介していきたいと思います。では、みおちゃんからどうぞ！
Alright, with that said, let's do self-introductions. Mio-chan, go ahead!
はい！えー、うちうち、うちだよ！おおかみみおだよ！ホロライブゲーマーズのおおかみみおです！
Hi! Um, house, house, it's me! Ookami Mio! I'm Ookami Mio of Hololive Gamers!
はい、次！はい、ホロライブ2期生！大空スバルでーす！よろしくお願いしまーす！
Next! Yes, Hololive 2nd Gen! Oozora Subaru-desu! Nice to meet you!
はい、ホロライブ5期生、獅白ぼたん です。獅子ロボたん、獅子ロボたん！
Hi, I'm Shishiro Botan from Hololive 5th Gen. Shishiro Botan, Shishiro Botan!
はい、コンピココンピココンピコ！ホロライブ3期生の、うさだぺこら、ぺこーだと、あーもんど、あーもんど！
Hi, con-peko con-peko! Usada Pekora from Hololive 3rd Gen, peko-da, and almond, almond!
はい、ということで、今日このメンバーでやるのは心合わせて魔力を集める団結ボックス！
Alright, with that said, what we're doing with this member today is the Unity Box to combine our hearts and gather magic power!
いや待って、うるさいわ！
Wait a second, you guys are noisy!
みんなうるさいわ、見なさいこれ！
You're all so loud, look at this!
うるさいわ、こちら見て！
Quiet down and look over here!
箱じゃんけん...なんだこれ？
Box rock-paper-scissors...? What's this?
この箱にはですね、魔力を集めている恐ろしいネコが封じ込められている...
Inside this box, a terrifying cat gathering magic is sealed away...
猫？猫なんていな...いよ！
A cat? There's no cat... here!
僕がこの団結ボックスの猫だにゃん。
I'm the cat of this Unity Box, nya~.
このボックスから出すお題に合わせて、みんなの心が合っていることを証明できたら、僕の魔力をトワに分けてあげてもいいよ～！
If your hearts match the prompt from this box,
I'll share my magic with Towa~!
まず始めに、「猫又おかゆ」っぽいポーズを全員で揃えてみてね～！
First, try matching a Nekomata Okayu-style pose together~!
ということで、この猫が説明してくれたように、トワたちの心は一つにして、お題に答えていけば、魔力がもらえて、トワは重大発表ができるんだよ、アンダーシュタンダ？
So, as that cat explained, if we unite our hearts
and answer the prompts, Towa can make her announcement!
よくわかんないけど、まずは、おかゆっぽいポーズを全員で揃えればいいってことですね！
I don't really get it, but basically we just need
to match an Okayu pose together!
ここから、お互いが見えない状態で、猫からのお題に答えていきます。あくまで猫呼びなんだよね。ゆげ猫ね、ゆげ猫から...
We'll answer the cat's prompts without seeing each other.
We're calling her a cat, right? Steam cat...
そうしましたら最初のお題は、猫又おかゆっぽいポーズを全員一致でス！
Alright, the first prompt is:
Everyone must match a Nekomata Okayu-style pose!
3、2、1、ポーズ！
3, 2, 1, pose!
みおちゃんしゃがんでね！
Mio-chan, you're squatting!
おかゆ一緒じゃね？
Isn't this Okayu's pose?
いや違う！待って待って！
No, wait, wait!
これは、猫又おかゆの、ビジュアルだよね、確か！
This is Nekomata Okayu's visual pose, right!
だってこう、こうだもんねでも、だってさ、マグカップじゃない？
Because it's like this, right? But wait,
isn't it a mug?
むち見たもん！
I saw Muchi!
これはシンパ！
This is sync!
やっぱ悪魔になりてえんだな
You really want to be a demon, huh.
では次ののお題はこちら、パン！常闇トワといえば？で思いつくポーズを全員バラバラだって！
Now, the next prompt is boom!
"A pose for Tokoyami Towa? Everyone different!"
バラバラでしょ？バラバラにしなきゃいけない。そうだよ、トワっぽいポーズだ全員バラバラだ。
It has to be different? We have to make them different.
Yeah, Towa-style poses, everyone must be different.
だからトワは、あれやるから、みんなはトワのやつやんないで！
So Towa will do that one,
you guys don't do Towa's!
じゃあいいですか？いきますよ！
Alright, are you ready? Here we go!
では、常闇トワっぽいポーズバラバラまで、3、2、1、ポン！
Now, for the Towa-style poses, everyone different,
until 3, 2, 1, pom!
おっ、どう？バラバラじゃん！これ成功じゃん！
Oh, how is it? They're all different!
This is a success!
やったー！すごい！成功！やったー！
Yay! Amazing! Success! Yay!
どうだろう？
How is it?
トワっぽいかどうか確認したいからね。
We want to check if it's Towa-like.
え、いや、言っとくけど一番トワっぽくないって。
Well, I'm telling you, it's the least Towa-like.
待って待って、一番！
Wait, wait, the most!
一番トワっぽくないって。
The least Towa-like.
え、え、待って待って。
Wait, wait, wait.
なんだこれ、なんだこれ。
What is this, what is this?
これはロボットですやん。
This is a robot, you know.
ああ、ロボットね。
Ah, a robot.
ロボットね。さっきロボットの真似してたからさ。
A robot. Because you were imitating a robot earlier.
確かに。ずっとね、ずっとロボットのポーズして...
True. You were doing the robot pose the whole time...
しゃあない、しゃあない。
It can't be helped.
ちょ、でもこれはしゃあてもう、だってえ。
But you know, this is fine because...
可愛かったし、可愛かったし、可愛かったから。
It was cute, it was cute, it was cute.
まぁきょう。
Well, today.
いやでもセーフ、セーフ！
No, but safe, safe!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
やった！
Yay!
いや緩いかって、いいのか今日。
Is it okay to be this lenient today?
でもさ、楽しければよくない？
But you know, as long as it's fun, isn't that fine?
まぁそれはそうだな。
Well, that's true.
はい、ということで次の話題はこちら。
Alright, so the next topic is this.
ぽん！
Boom!
水着でするポーズといえば？で思いつくポーズを全員バラバラ！
What pose comes to mind when you think of swimwear? Everyone different!
え、でもこれさ、
Eh, but this...
ホロライブサマーがあるからいけるだろ！
Hololive Summer is happening, so we can do it!
いける！
We can!
でも、バラバラだよ？バラバラ。
But it has to be different, right? Different.
バラバラか。
Different, huh.
水着でしょ？
Swimwear, right?
でもみんなさ、あのさ、撮ったじゃんし水着の写真。
But everyone, you know, we took swimsuit photos.
撮った！撮った！
We did! We did!
それさ、一一緒のポーズだったらやばいからさ、全員バラバラのね
If we did the exact same pose, that'd be bad, so everyone has different...
自分のポーズを。
your own pose.
そう、自分のポーズをすればさ、可愛いしいいんじゃね？
Right, if you do your own pose, wouldn't it be cute and good?
確かに。
True.
いや、もう決まった。
No, I've already decided.
え、どういうポーズだったっけ？
Eh, what kind of pose was it?
見こら！
Miko-ora!
でもさ、被んないようにしっかり考えよう。
But let's think carefully so we don't overlap.
それだった。
It was this.
オッケー、じゃあいきますよ。
Okay, then let's go.
水着でするポーズ、全員バラバラまで、
Swimwear pose, everyone different, ready...
3、2、1、ぽん！
3, 2, 1, boom!
こうだった気がして。
I felt like it was like this.
こうじゃなかった。
It wasn't like this.
え、どう？
Eh, what?
え、どう？え、どう？
Eh, what? Eh, what?
え、なんか、みここんとこボタン？
Eh, Miko, where's the button?
あれ？角度が違う。
Huh? The angle is different.
こう。
Like this.
え、のーこ、被ってるように見える？
Eh, Noko, does it look like it overlaps?
いや、被ってない。
No, it doesn't overlap.
私の手前なの。
Mine is in front.
違う。
That's wrong.
手前なの本なの。
Mine is in front.
あの、ボタンは手を前で、みおは手を...
Uh, Botan has hands in front, Mio has hands...
うちは手を上です。
I have my hands up.
手を上！
Hands up!
で、ぺこらちゃんはハート？
And Pekora-chan is heart?
うん、ハート。
Yeah, heart.
え、スバちゃんは元気で、トワこう、こういう感じで。
And Subaru-chan is energetic, and Towa is like this, like this.
え、じゃあこれクリアじゃない？
Eh, then isn't this cleared?
やったー！
Yay!
めっちゃ嬉しーこれ！
I'm so happy about this!
いやこれは、全員バラバラはいいよね。
Well, everyone being different is good, right?
いや、振り付け上手かったわ。
No, the choreography was good.
あれ、あれ、やばい、ちょっとやっちゃったかな。
Oh, oh, oh, oh, maybe I messed up a bit.
でもね、次はね、わかんないから。
But you know, next we won't know.
え、いいじゃん、やっちゃっていいんだよだって。
Eh, it's fine, you can do it.
なんか、簡単すぎる。
It's like, too easy.
え、いいのこんな簡単で。
Eh, is it okay being this easy?
やだ、10ポイントとか稼ぎたくねえよ。
No way, I don't want to earn like 10 points.
なんでだよ！
Why not!
10ポイントとかさしてくんねえよ。
You won't let me get 10 points.
確かに、やっぱエネミー側なんだ。
True, after all we're on the enemy side.
はい。
Alright.
ということで、じゃあ次。
With that, next.
はい。
Yes.
次の話題はこちら、ぽん！
The next prompt is this, boom!
アイドルポーズといえば？で思いつくポーズを全員一致！
What pose comes to mind when you think of an idol pose? Everyone match!
これちょっと話し合わんといかんわ。
We need to discuss this a bit.
まず、誰のアイドルポーズにするかだ。
First, whose idol pose should we use?
確かに。
True.
一旦仕切り直します。
Let's reset once.
誰のアイドルポーズ？
Whose idol pose?
え、え、待って。これ普通にゆ...
Eh, eh, wait. Just normally...
え、ちゃう？誰にする？
Eh, really? Who should we do?
わかりやすい人にしようよ。
Let's pick someone easy to understand.
ソラ先輩とか。
Sora-senpai, or someone.
えー！そら先輩？
Ehh! Sora-senpai?
いや、多分、そら先輩だったら多分...
Well, probably, if it's Sora-senpai...
え、あれしかないと思うな、あぺこらは。
Eh, I think there's only that one, Pekora.
あれ？あれって何？
Huh? What is that?
え、あれじゃない？
Eh, isn't it that?
でもこれさ、ミスったらなんか結構大ダメージおいそうじゃね？
But you know, if we mess up, we're gonna take huge damage, right?
保険かけよ、保険かけ、保険かけよ。
Let's get insurance, get insurance.
もう、そらスバルにしようよ。
Let's just make it Sora and Subaru.
そらスバル？保険のスバルも...
Sora and Subaru? Insurance Subaru too...
確かに。
True.
そらスバルもわかんないな。そらスバルはもう公式のページあるじゃん。
Sora and Subaru we don't know either. Sora and Subaru already have an official page.
なるほど、あれよ、あのポーズだろ。
I see, that, that pose.
えー！待って、どれだ？
Ehh! Wait, which one?
あの、絶妙なのがあんねんて、絶妙なのが。なんかあった気がする。
That, there's an exquisite one, an exquisite one. I feel like there was one.
絶妙な。
Exquisite.
え？
Eh?
わかんねえ。
I don't know.
でもさ、やっぱ船長、船長じゃない？
But you know, isn't it Marine, Marine-sencho?
船長じゃない？船長。
Isn't it Sencho? Sencho.
確かに。マリンのアイドルポーズってこと？
True. You mean Marine's idol pose?
うん。マリンかぺこちゃんなが、ぺこちゃんも分かりやすい気がする。
Yeah. Marine or Pekora-chan, Pekora-chan also feels easy to understand.
ペコちゃんなら分かりやすい。
Pekora-chan is easy to understand.
いつもあのポーズしてるわってしてるな。
She's always doing that pose, we know.
え、やばいだけど、自分でこうしてるとか。
Eh, that's bad though, if we do it ourselves.
ぺこちゃん分からないって言ってるぞ。
Pekora says she doesn't know.
ペコちゃんは分からないけど、いつもしてる。
Pekora doesn't know, but always does it.
じゃあ、ぺこちゃんにしよう、ぺこちゃんにしよう。
Then let's do Pekora-chan, let's do Pekora-chan.
え、どれにするか？
Eh, which one?
ペコラ...え、ちょっと待って、大丈夫？
Pekora... Eh, wait a minute, is it okay?
アイドルポーズといえばで思いつくポーズ全員一致で揃えろ！
What pose comes to mind when you think of an idol? Everyone match and align!
せーの！
Ready, go!
これだ！
This is it!
え、みんな合ってます？
Eh, does everyone match?
ペコラの...
Pekora's...
それさ、それさ、これじゃない？のじゃね？それ。
Wait, isn't that this? Isn't it that?
これか。
This.
そうそう。
Yeah, yeah.
え、どこでしてんのそれ？
Eh, where do you do that?
いや、してるやん、してるしてるしてる。
No, you do it, you do it.
あ、ぺこちゃんの手のやつの。
Ah, Pekora-chan's hand thing.
あ、立ち絵的に？
Ah, in terms of official art?
こうか。
Like this.
そう、トワは。
Yeah, Towa is...
全員寄ってねって言ったじゃん。
Didn't you say everyone gather?
あれ？
Huh?
え、待って、これペコちゃん難しくない？
Eh, wait, isn't this hard for Pekora?
ぺこぱじゃねぇし。
It's not Pekopa.
ペコだろ。
It's Peko.
こう、こうね。
Like this, like this.
あ、そうだっけ。
Oh, that's right.
え、どうだっけ？
Wait, do you?
いや待って、私たちまだハート作ってない気がする、こうやってポーズ。
Wait, we haven't even made hearts yet, have we?
それハートじゃない、サンバ！
It's not that kind of game.
サンバじゃん！
That's the samba!
そうだっけ。
That's right.
あー、サンバか。
Ah, samba, huh?
なるほどね。
Well, you know.
はい。
Yeah.
ということで、えー、
So, with that said...
じゃあ次はどうぞ、ポン！
Next, go ahead, pon!
ポン！
Pon!
なんだ？
What is it?
猫又おかゆがメスを注入してる時のポーズを全員一致！
"Nekomata Okayu's pose when administering the scalpel" - everyone must match!
え、それどういうことなん？
Wait, what does that mean?
え、これ、おかゆからのお題なんですけど、
Wait, is this Okayu's prompt?
他人にメスを注入してる時ってこと？
Is it injecting a scalpel into someone else?
自分に、自分にじゃなくて、どっち？
Wait, you inject it into yourself?
自分にどう注入するの？
How do you inject it into yourself?
メスを注入する、そのポーズってこと？
Administering a scalpel? Is that a pose?
どういうこと？解釈すればいいの、これは。
How should we interpret this?
いやでも、今は自分のすばちゃんのをみんな見ちゃったから。
Well, but now everyone saw Subaru's, so...
待って待って、覗いて！覗いて！覗いて！
Wait, everyone's peeking!
他人のじゃない、他人の。
It's not someone else's, right?
やばいだろ。
That's crazy!
なんか、遅いかかってるみたいな感じじゃない？
It's like it's coming late, isn't it?
自分にじゃないの、これ。
Isn't it into yourself?
え、自分になの？自分、やっぱね、メスを入れて、メスになりたいからさ。
Into yourself? To become a scalpel?
え、なんかやばいポーズ取られそうで怖いいんだけど。
Wait, coming up with a dangerous pose is scary, though.
正解わかんねえ。
I don't know the right answer.
じゃあもうとりあえず、もうそこはもうおまかせでやるか。
Well, let's just go with whatever.
やばいよな！早くヒントかけてくれ！
That's crazy! Give us a hint!
できればいいけど、難しすぎるんだよ別。スキットして、スキットして！
If you can do that, it's too difficult. Just sketch it!
ヒントくれよ！え、じゃあもう、行くよこれ。
Give us a hint, let's go!
え、ということで、猫又おかゆがメスを注入してる時のポーズを全員一致！
So, Nekomata Okayu's pose when administering a scalpel—everyone match!
せーの！
Ready, go!
もう、こう、こうしかなくない？こういう感じじゃない？
Wait, like this? Like this?
お！ぺこらちゃんは中腰でしょ？
Oh! Pekora's crouching?
みおちゃんは、え、それ注入されてるポーズじゃなくて。
Mio-chan, wait, that's not a pose of being injected...
でも、やっぱなんか座ってるのがあるかなみたいなイメージ。
Yeah, sitting down while staying clean, maybe.
確かに、やっぱ座りながらよ。注射のポーズはしたけど。
Yeah, exactly, while sitting down. I did the injection pose.
じゃあ私もさ、さっきこれだったから、やばいな。やばい！
And I was just doing this earlier, it's crazy!
ということで、おかゆからの御題は、失敗！
Okayu's prompt result is... Failure!
ちょっと全然合わないじゃん！
It doesn't match at all!
いや、そんなこと言われてもお題難しいよ。
Even if you say that, the prompt is too hard.
ギリギリ立ってるよ、俺らはこうやって。こうやって。
I'm standing right on the edge, like this.
大丈夫、ライン踏んでも超えなきゃ大丈夫だから。
It's fine even if you cross the line, as long as you don't fall off.
はい、ということで仕切りボーン、ちょっとカンニングしちゃだめだからね。
Alright, partition wall, no peeking!
はい、えーでは次の御題どうぞ、ポン！
Next prompt, please, pon!
お化け屋敷でびっくりした常闇トワのポーズを全員一致！
"Towa-sama's pose when startled in a haunted house" - everyone match!
え、じゃあもうトワが正解ってこと？
So Towa is the correct answer?
え、びっくりした時のポーズでしょ？もう決まりでしょ、こんなの。
It's the pose when you're startled, right? It's decided!
え、ぺこらのとこ、トワさん、これ何個かっていうのがあるけどさ。でも、可愛いもあるわ。
Pekora says Towa-san has a few patterns, and cute ones too.
まあ、出たとこ勝負でやるか。じゃあ出たとこ勝負よ。
Well, let's just do a showdown.
じゃあ行きますよ、せーの！
Here we go! Ready, go!
あれ？え？どう？
Huh? What?
ぺこちゃん、可愛い。
Pekora-chan's is cute!
トワはもうこれ、これこれ正解だからこれ。
Towa, this is... this is the right answer.
すばるちゃんのをさ、狙ってるだろ、面白い。
Subaru-chan's, you're aiming, that's funny!
トワは、とんでもないことが起こった時にテンパりすぎて。
Towa, when something crazy happens, you panic so much.
いや、違うよ！全然違うくない！
No, that's not it!
でも待って、みおちゃんもしゃがんでたよ。あ、でも似てる。
Wait, Mio-chan was crouching too.
もっとこう可愛い感じだよ、トワは。
It's more of a cute vibe, Towa!
はあ！？こっちだ！
Ha?! Over here!
なんで正解がさ、怒られなきゃいけないの。
Why is the correct answer getting scolded?
みんな全然わかってないよ！
Everyone really doesn't get it!
失敗！頼むわ、マジで。
Failure! I'm begging you, seriously.
一致したいわ。
I want to get it right.
はい、では次、ドン！
Alright, then next, boom!
夏と聞いて思い浮かぶものを全員一致！
"What comes to mind when you hear 'summer'" - everyone must match!
よっしゃ！
Let's go!
後ろを見てください、皆さん！
Look behind you, guys!
おっ！
Oh!
あっ、あるある！
Ah, there are!
なんかいろいろあるじゃん。
There's a lot of stuff.
何これ？
What is this?
ちょっと、み、
Wait...
い、あるよ。
What's this?
水鉄砲？
Water gun?
かき氷だ！
Shaved ice...
本当だ。
True.
おー！
Oh!
かき氷とかもあるんじゃない？
Shaved ice...
かき氷とスイカだ！
Shaved ice! Watermelon!
スイカだ！
Watermelon!
あ、スイカだ！
Ah, watermelon!
50種類ぐらいかな？
There are about 50 kinds, right?
おお、いろいろある！
Oh! There are a lot.
で、この中で、
So, among these,
夏と言えば、夏と言ったら思い浮かぶ？
if we say "summer"... what do you think?
きれんなって！
That's too fast!
おまえの選ぶの早すぎるだろ！
That's too fast! Too fast!
夏ときいて思い浮かぶものを、
What you think of when you hear "summer"...
一瞬で全員一致よ！
Unanimously! Everyone!
夏と言えばね。
If we say "summer"...
いや、これ一瞬で決ま、夏っしょ？
Well, this is decided in an instant. Summer, right?
夏っしょ？
Summer, right?
いや、これさあ。
No, this...
これしかないでしょ、これしかない。
It has to be this!
決めた？
Have you decided?
決めたかな？
決めた！
I've decided.
自分が思い浮かべたやつでいいよね？
You can decide on what you think of, right?
いいよ、いいよ。
Yeah, yeah.
全員一致でよ？
Unanimously, right?
はい。
Yes.
じゃあ、せーので後ろ振り返って見せよう、みんなで。
Okay, ready? Turn around and show everyone!
いくよ？
Here we go!
せーの、どん！
Ready, go!
わー！
Watermelon!
スイカ！
えっ、ちょっと待って、あれ多くない？
Wait, wait, wait! Extra?
あれ、追加？
Wait, extra?
追加！
Extra?
Extra!
あれ、かき氷！
That's shaved ice!
かき氷は。
Shaved ice.
なんかお祭りじゃん。
That's festival-themed, right?
かき氷は。
Shaved ice is...
ちょ、待っ、あはははは！
Oh, wait!
めっちゃ焦げた！
She panicked!
焦げました！焦げました！焦げました！
I panicked! I panicked!
夏だよね、ほんと。
It has to be summer, right?
夏だよね！
Summer, right?
え、待って、ボタン！
Botan!
ボタン！
夏だよね！
It's summer!
待って、でも答え変わっ、あの、答え合ってねえから！
Wait, the answers are different—the answers don't match, right?
違っただけです。違っただけです。
Only Botan's answer is different!
じゃあこっちは、不正解っていうことでね！
So that means it's wrong!
なんで、違うの？
Why? How?
なんでだよ。
Why?
待ってよ。
Wait, you guys...
だってさ、みんなトワの配信だからって、
Since you're all in Towa's stream,
暴れちらかしてるでしょ！
you're just acting wild!
いや、トワが暴れ、
No, we're not!
暴れてんじゃねえの、これ！
We're not acting wild, right?
そうだな、そうだな。
That's right, that's right.
お前が一番暴れてって。
You were the most wild!
やめて！
Stop it!
はい、じゃあ、次。
Okay, then...
じゃあ、次、どん！
Okay, then next, don!
やばいよ、全然当たってないよ。
Wait, none of them have been correct yet!
海で遊びたいものを全員一致！
What you want to do at the beach—unanimously!
これは、これだ、これだ！
This is—I want this!
これはもう、これだな。
This is...
これ、あれだぞ、食べ物で遊ぶなっていうの出てくるぞ。
This—wait, this is playing with food!
そうだね。
Ah, that's right.
あ、そうだね。
海で遊びたいもので行こうかと、おも、思いますよ。
Well, let's go with what we want to do at the beach.
決まった？みんな。
Have you decided, everyone?
決まった！決まった！
Got it! Got it!
決まった！
Got it!
え、海で遊びたいもの、いくよ、せーの、これ！
Things we want to do at the beach—ready, go!
水鉄砲じゃねえなあ！
Water gun? No way!
ぼたんちゃん、全然、全部合ってないじゃん！
Botan, you didn't—you didn't match at all!
はよ。
Quick!
なんか選んじゃったの、独特だな。
Wait, your answers are unique!
もう持てなくなってるじゃん。
You can't even hold it up!
これ！
It's a water gun!
最後尾にしてんだろ、最後尾に。
You're putting it on your head!
やばい、これは。
That's crazy!
ボタンだけ水鉄砲でしょ、これ。
Only Botan has a water gun!
一人で遊んどこ、これ。
Let's play alone!
悲しい、寂しすぎる。
Sad!
はい、というわけで、え、なんと、
Okay, so next—
次で最終問題で。
this is the final question!
えっ？マジ？
Seriously?
えっ、マジ？
全然当たってないじゃん。
Not matching at all!
いや、全然揃ってない、全然揃ってないじゃん！
Wait, you're not matching at all!
重大発表なしで。
No major announcement for us!
これ、ここで終わるんじゃね？
Is it going to end here?
大丈夫、ここってか、1個当たってるから。
It's fine, we got one right.
大丈夫じゃねえよ。
It's not fine, right?
じゃあ、最後当ててね。
Let's get the last one right!
綺麗に。
Right?
そうね、まあ、まあ、そうだね。
Yeah, well, that's right.
最後を綺麗に飾りましょう。
Let's decorate the end nicely!
ということで、最後のお題はこちら！
So, the final question is this!
常闇トワとかぶらないものを選べ！
Choose something that doesn't match Tokoyami Towa!
かぶらないもの？
Something that doesn't match?
かぶっちゃダメか。
We mustn't match?
いや、これトワだったらこれでいったれやね！
If it's Towa, we have to go with this!
え、ということだと、じゃあトワとかぶんなきゃいけないってこと？
So that means we shouldn't match Towa?
そう、トワとかぶんなきゃいいってこと。
No, we shouldn't match Towa!
これで行くわ。
We'll go with this!
でも、他とトワがかぶってもいいんだよね？
Even if it matches Towa, it's fine, right?
そうそうそうそう。決まった？
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Got it?
決まった。オッケー。あっ、ごめん、ちょっと待って。えっと、
Got it. Okay, wait, wait.
かぶらないものね。そうだよ。
Something that doesn't match...
オッケー。いい？
Okay. Is it good?
うん、オッケー。
Okay.
いくよ？
Here we go!
まじで、頼むよ、最後だよ。
Make sure it doesn't match! It's the last one!
はい、いくよ。せーの、これ！
Here we go, ready, go!
かぶってる！
Wait, they match!
They match!
かぶってる！
アイスクリーム！
Ice cream!
で、こっちは？
And this is—
成功！
Success!
やっぱ最後は決めたんだよ！
You nailed the last one!
すごっ！
That's amazing!
ということは？
That means—
最後は決めた！
You nailed the last one!
かったの、みんなすごい！
Everyone is amazing!
わかってないから。
Since you didn't know,
わかんないから成功したんだ。
Since you didn't know, it was a success!
そういうことか。
Is that it?
え、というわけで、これまでの結果は、おっ。
So, the result of all this is—
9問中。
Out of 9 questions...
3問成功！
3 questions correct!
すごーい！
Amazing!
これでいいでしょ。どうですか？
That's fine, right? How is it?
おっ。
Oh!
言っていなかったけど、
I didn't say it before,
全てのお題を成功させないと、
but unless you succeed in all the questions,
僕の「魔力」は分けられないからね〜。
my "magic" can't be shared, you know?
残念だったね。
Too bad.
みんなが頑張っている姿は可愛かったよ。
Seeing everyone try their best was cute, though.
それじゃね！
Oh well!
なんだよこれー！
What is this?
分けたかったー！
I wanted it!
え？
Eh?
え、いいじゃない？
Eh, isn't that good?
え、あの箱、箱壊して、なんか魔力...
Eh, breaking that box, somehow magic...
いや、やっちゃお、やっちゃお、ねえ、もう
No, let's do it, let's do it, hey now.
やっちゃおかな、とか思ったけど、なんかみんなと楽しく遊んでたら
I thought about doing it, but when playing happily with everyone,
すごい、なんか魔力が、からだじゅうからみんな出てきちゃってさ
wow, somehow magic started coming out from all over our bodies.
え、ちょっと待って。魔力って我々も感じることができる？
Eh, wait a minute. Can we feel magic too?
やってみ...あ、できるかも。
Try i... Ah, maybe we can.
うそ？
Really?
何や、何や、なんかすごいことになってゆいましたわ、今。
What, what, something amazing just happened.
なんかね、ちょっと壊れちゃったみたいとわね。
It seems like it broke a bit, Towa-ne.
重大発表ができるように出しといた！
I brought it out so we can make a major announcement!
重大発表には、重大発表にふさわしいステージがあるペコなんじゃないですか？
Isn't there a stage worthy of a major announcement, Peko?
あるのよ、あるのよ、あるのよ、あるのよ、ねえ。
There is, there is, there is, there is, right.
心情の奥様がお前は
Your true feelings are...
あるのよ、あるのよって。ちょっと待って。準備できてますからね、みなさん、いいかしら？
There is, there is. Wait a minute. We're ready, everyone, is that okay?
あ、ちょっと、あ、ちょっと、マジでがんばりたいから、落ち着いていってくるわ。
Ah, wait, ah, wait, I really want to do my best, so I'll go calm down.
いってらっしゃい！
Have fun!
みんな、聞こえてる？
Everyone, can you hear me?
はい！ 改めまして本ライブ4期生の常闇トワです！
Yes! Once again, this is Tokoyami Towa from the 4th generation!
ゲストとの絆チェックどうだったかな？ トワはね、楽しかったよ！
How was the bond check with the guests? Towa had fun!
はい、そしてね、なんとゲストのみんなと楽しんだあとは歌、ライブパートで盛り上がりましょう！
Yes, and after having fun with all the guests, let's get hyped with the singing and live part!
みんな、盛り上がる準備はできているかー！
Everyone, are you ready to get hyped?!
うおお！ って言ってくれてるだろう。はい！
Whoa! You're probably saying that. Yes!
ライブパート中には、超、超、超重大発表があるので、最後までお見逃しなく！
During the live part, there's a super, super, super major announcement, so don't miss it till the very end!
一体、どんな発表なのか。
Just what kind of announcement is it?
ドキドキが止まらない！
My heart won't stop pounding!
ということで、みんなは楽しみだよねえ！
So, everyone's looking forward to it, right!
はい！ それでは、開演までもう少々お待ちください！
Yes! Well then, please wait just a little longer until the show starts!
以上、常闇トワ様でした！ バイちゃ！
That's all, Tokoyami Towa-sama! Bye-cha!
生れた赤い花
Born red flowers
只、孤独にゆらゆら
Only, swaying in solitude
解答の無い叢
With no answers
弁明は脆弱に愚かな結局
Excuses are fragile, foolish conclusions
禍にされ心は泣いてる
The crucified heart is weeping
両手から落ちるこの滴が
These drops falling from both hands
だって私は いつまでもずっと お姫様
After all, I'll always be a princess.
キミ以外はもうありえない
Anything other than you is impossible now.
ちょっといつもフラフラ 散歩向こうの 思わせぶり
Always acting fickle and leading others on.
許さないからね 好きだよって
I won't forgive you. Saying "I love you"
恋なんて 褒めかして もっと
like romance, coaxing me more—
骨までしゃぶって
pick me to the bone!
無理だよって 焦るよって
Saying "No way," making me panic—
からす ハートを振り回して
crowing, tossing my heart around.
骨も髄までしゃぶり尽くして
Sucking me dry to the marrow,
壊れるほど惑わせて
bewitching me to the point of breaking.
You know, You know, You know... 浴びる程転がして
You know, you know, you know... rolling me around till I'm saturated.
時給の音を駆け巡って シビル声は ライメイ
Racing through the ticking sound, the paralyzing voice is Raimei.
勝手な妄想なんだけど
It's just a selfish delusion, but
こっちむいて キミ以外はもう愛せない
look this way! I can't love anyone but you.
ちょっと気分屋なんだけど
I can be a bit moody, but
いつか私 気持ち狂いそうってが
Someday, my feelings might go crazy,
気づいちゃって 気づいちゃって
realizing it, realizing it,
気づけたい事故
wanting to notice the accident.
これは サンクチュアリ
This is a sanctuary,
禁断の愛ぞ
forbidden love.
自分をそこでなづけて
Pat yourself on the back right there,
ぬくい鳥かごを長くして
and lengthen that cozy birdcage.
はずいくらいの笑顔で
With an embarrassing smile,
You know, You know, You know... その最後まで踏てきたのに
You know, you know, you know... even though I stepped all the way to the end,
やばい急のの見落としが
a dangerous oversight—
闇を終わらすほど
enough to end the darkness,
どしたって
no matter what.
君次第で もっとちょうだい 幻だって 雑音ライアー
If it's up to you, give me more, even if it's an illusion, you noisy liar.
このまま地獄へ とざいぞ
Into hell just like this, step right in.
Lou, Lou, Lou, Lou...
からす ハートを振り回して
Tossing my heart around,
再び今までが全部 あなた自身の心だって
Until now, everything was your very own heart.
You know, You know, You know... 留めて平らで転がして
You know, you know, you know... rolling me around smoothly.
私だけを愛していて 壊れていくほど
Love only me, to the point of breaking.
痺れる声は ライメイ
The paralyzing voice is Raimei.
青い惑星に生まれて
Born on a blue planet,
違う道を歩いて たどり着いたこの街
walking a different path, I arrived in this city.
光る粒が弾けた
Shining particles burst forth.
巡る夜にキミと出会い いつの間にか手を繋いで
Meeting you in the revolving night, before I knew it, holding hands.
笑い声と弾む足で どこまでも走れるミッドナイト
With laughter and bouncing steps, Midnight where we can run anywhere.
見上けた空星の光 街のネオンが混ざり合って
Looking up at the starlight in the sky, blending with the city neon,
憂鬱な日々を忘れて
forgetting the gloomy days.
痛い・辛いとか、苦い・暗いはもう全部捨て去って
Throwing away all the pain, hardship, bitterness, and darkness,
ボクらもっと自由なはず
we should be much freer.
閉ざした羽を開いたなら
If we open our closed wings,
退屈な日々にはさようなら
say goodbye to tedious days
夜の街を行こう
and head out into the night city.
さあ
Now,
ビルを抜けて 街を追い越して
slipping through buildings and overtaking the city,
さらば青い惑星
farewell, blue planet.
なんて惚けてどこまで行こう
Fascinated, how far shall we go?
変わらないものなど何もないから
Since nothing stays the same,
たった一つ 確かな今を刻んで
carve out just one certain present.
踊る夜にキミを連れて 邪魔なものは何もなくて
Taking you along into the dancing night, with nothing in our way,
歌う声と軽い足で いつでも走れるミッドナイト
with a singing voice and light steps, Midnight where we can always run.
見上けた空月の光 街の幻想が惹かれあって
Looking up at the moonlight, drawn to the city's illusions,
憂鬱な日々を忘れて
forgetting the gloomy days,
痛い・辛いとか、苦い・暗いはもう全部捨て去って
throwing away all the pain, hardship, bitterness, and darkness.
描けない今を刻んで
Engraving the unpaintable present,
踊る夜にキミを連れて
Taking you along into the dancing night,
邪魔なものは何もなくて
with nothing in our way at all,
歌う声と軽い足で
with a singing voice and light steps,
いつまでも駆けるミッドナイト
running forever into the midnight.
見上げた空月の光
Looking up at the moonlight in the sky,
街の幻想が惹かれ合って
the town's illusions attract one another.
鬱屈な日々を忘れて
Forgetting those gloomy days,
痛い・辛いとか、苦い・暗いはもう全部捨て去って
throwing away all the pain, hardship, bitterness, and darkness!
見上げた空星の光
Looking up at the starlight in the sky,
街のネオンが混ざり合って
the town's neon lights blend together.
退屈な日々にさようなら
Saying goodbye to boring days,
ボクの手を取ってさあ
take my hand, come on!
常世の闇に囚われたまま
Trapped within the everlasting darkness,
奏でる悲鳴を (聴かせて)
playing out that cry of sorrow (let me hear it).
さあ 爪を磨いたら
Come on, once you've sharpened your claws,
まだ子供のようなあなたの為に
for you, who are still like a child—
常世の闇に囚われたまま
Trapped within the everlasting darkness,
甘い甘いガムを噛んでた
chewing on sweet, sweet gum.
いくつの後悔を捧げて
Offering up how many regrets,
さりげない合図に隠れた
hidden within a casual signal—
答えはすぐにわからせてあげる
I'll make you understand the answer right away.
微笑な嘘にまみれた
Smeared in smiling lies,
拒んだままに 受け止めてあげる
just as you refused, I'll accept you.
ほら悲鳴を聞かせて
Come on, let me hear your cries of sorrow.
さりげない合図に隠れた
Hidden within a casual signal—
答えはすぐにわからせてあげる
I'll make you understand the answer right away.
微笑な嘘にまみれた
Smeared in smiling lies,
拒んだままに 受け止めてあげる
just as you refused, I'll accept you.
ほら悲鳴を聞かせて
Come on, let me hear your cries of sorrow.
さあ 指を鳴らしたら
Come on, once you snap your fingers,
この子猫のような私のために
for someone like me, who's like this kitten—
喉が渇いたわ 薄紅の口に指を散らして
my throat is parched, scattering my fingers across pale crimson lips.
狭い牢獄に閉じ込めたまま
Kept locked inside a narrow prison cell,
首輪に繋がれたいんでしょ?
you want to be chained by the collar, don't you?
くだらないルールじゃ奪えない
You can't steal it with trivial rules—
自由はすでにこの手の中にある
freedom is already right here in my hands.
愛情では計れない
It cannot be measured by affection,
弱ったままで選ばせてあげる
I'll let you choose while you remain weak.
ほら心を開いて
Come on, open your heart.
わからないふりをして寝ぼけてるの?
Are you pretending not to understand and dozing off?
もっと熱い闇を見せて?ねえ?
Show me a much hotter darkness, won't you?
馬鹿なふりをして
Pretending to be a fool,
猫被っての もっと熱い暗闇を見せて
putting on a cat's facade—show me an even hotter darkness!
ねえ
Hey...
さりげない合図に隠れた
Hidden within a casual signal—
答えはすぐにわからせてあげる
I'll make you understand the answer right away.
微笑な嘘にまみれた
Smeared in smiling lies,
拒んだままに 受け止めてあげる
just as you refused, I'll accept you.
都合の闇に 刻むこの名を
Engraving this name into the darkness of convenience—
わからせてあげる
I'll make you understand.
ほら悲鳴を聞かせてよ
Come on, let me hear your cries of sorrow.
決意見ないで
Don't look at my resolve—
ほら聞かせて
come on, let me hear it.
生まれた赤い花
A red flower was born,
只、孤独にゆらゆら
swaying alone and frail.
解答のない慄
A shudder with no answer,
弁明は脆く愚かな結末
an excuse is a fragile and foolish end.
禍にされた心は泣いている
The afflicted heart is crying.
両手から落ちるこの雫が
These droplets falling from both hands,
貴方には見えていないのでしょう
you probably cannot see them.
なら此処まで
If so, up to this point—
悲しい声に、コトバに、追い払われて
Driven away by sorrowful voices and words,
佇んだまま微笑む赤い花
a red flower smiles as it stands still.
深く根を張る痛みが贖罪なら
If the deeply rooted pain is atonement,
解り合えない
we cannot understand each other,
ずっとこのまま
always remaining this way.
変わらない定め
An unchanging destiny,
真理は不条理
truth is absurd.
剥き出しされた感覚の違い
The difference in bare sensations,
ありふれた“言葉”を振りかざす
wielding clichéd "words".
貴方には見えていないのでしょう
You probably cannot see them.
もう消せない傷
A wound that can no longer be erased,
風の吹く夜に
on a windy night,
散ってしまう花のものを
the flowers that scatter away—
貴方は知ることもきっとないのでしょう
you will surely never know them.
底の底まで墜ちたら黒い景色
Falling to the very bottom is a black scenery.
佇んだまま泣いていた赤い花
A red flower was crying as it stood still.
朽ちていく心の中 まだ願っている
Inside my decaying heart, I am still wishing
ありのままで生きていたいと
to live just as I am.
変わらない定め
An unchanging destiny,
視線には縋り
clinging to gazes,
吹き出しにされて
turned into speech bubbles,
感覚の違い
the difference in sensations.
ありふれて刃を繰り出す
Commonplace blades are brandished,
あなたには
and to you,
見えていないのでしょう
they probably cannot be seen.
もう消えない
A wound that can no longer
傷
be erased...
風の強さに 散ってしまう花の色は
The color of the flowers scattering in the strong wind,
あなたは知ることもきっとないのでしょう
you will surely never know it.
深くまで枯れた黒い景色
A black scenery withered deep down.
佇んだまま泣いていた 儚い花
A transient flower crying as it stood still.
朽ちていく心の中 まだ願ってる
Inside my decaying heart, I am still wishing
ありのまま 生きていたいと
to live just as I am.
歌いたいと
To want to sing.
悲しい声に、コトバに、
Driven away by sorrowful voices,
追い払われて
by words,
俯いたまま連れ行くアネモネ
an anemone carried away with a downturned gaze.
深く根を張る痛みが消えなくても
Even if the deeply rooted pain doesn't vanish,
藻掻き続ける
I will keep struggling.
何度のだって
No matter how many times,
儚い想いに
reaching out my hands
愛しい思いに
to a faint, beloved feeling,
手を伸ばして
stretching them out.
もっと自由にあるために 私を縛る XXXを壊せ
To be freer... Smash the XXX that binds me!
楽しいこういう言葉に追い越されてて うつむいたまま微笑む赤い花
Overtaken by joyful words like these, a red flower smiles with its head down.
深く乾いた痛みが生え際直ぐなら分かり合えない
Deep, dry pain right at the roots—we can never understand each other.
ずっとこのまま
Staying like this forever...
みんな、はーい。
Everyone, hii!
なんと！常闇トワのファーストアルバム発売と、そのライブの開催が決定しましたーーっ！
What's this?! Tokoyami Towa's 1st album release and its live concert have been decided!
やばいね、やばいもう本当に、今日まですごい、もうドキドキしてました、発表できる日。
This is crazy... I've been so nervous until today, waiting for the day I could announce this.
えー、ここからはね、大事な情報ばかりなので、えー、よく聞いてください。
Um, from here on out is important info, so please listen closely.
えー、まずは常闇トワ ファーストアルバム「ASTER」が、2023年今年9月27日に発売されます！
First, Tokoyami Towa's 1st album "ASTER" will be released on September 27th, 2023!
いや、すごい。あのー、なんていうの、神秘的なイラストだよね。はい、とっても素敵な、美しいトワになっております。
Wow, amazing. Um, it's such a mysterious illustration, right? Yes, Towa looks so wonderful and beautiful here.
はい、そのアルバムなんですけれども、みんな、すごい、えー、トワ様のソロアルバム欲しいて、すごい言ってくれてたんで、本当に発表できて嬉しいです。
Yes, about that album, everyone kept saying they wanted Towa-sama's solo album, so I'm really happy to finally announce it.
えー、このアルバムなんですけれども、すごいこだわって作ったので、作っているので、いま、えー、ぜひお楽しみにしといてください。マジで、えー、本当にすごいよ。
Um, this album was made with so much care and attention, so please look forward to it. Seriously, it's truly amazing.
はい。そしてなんと、あのー、こちらのアルバムの販売店でアルバムを買ってくれた方には特典が付きます！
Yes! And what's more, if you buy this album at these participating stores, you'll get special bonuses!
特典はこちら！
The bonuses are right here!
はい、いろんなね、お店があるんですけれど、お店ごとにいろんなね、特典があるので、みんなチェックしてみてください。
Yes, there are various stores, and each has different bonuses, so everyone please check them out.
あ、コメントありがと！マジ見えてるよ！楽しみ！とか、え、スパチャも嬉しいし、もういろんな人のコメントも嬉しいし、ライブ！とかね。
Ah, thanks for the comments! I can seriously see them! "Can't wait!" and stuff—super chat makes me happy, comments from everyone make me happy, "Live!" and all.
見えてるよ、みんな！ありがとう！
I can see you, everyone! Thank you!
みんなのおかげだよマジで。これガチでよ？ガチガチ。本当にありがとう、嬉しいよマジで。
It's all thanks to everyone, seriously. I mean it! Truly, thank you, I'm so happy, seriously.
もうこれからもね、えー配信したらしたらもう触れるんですけども。はい、で今日はね、その中からホロライブプロダクション公式オフィシャルショップの特典をお見せしちゃいます！
From now on too, whenever I stream I'll mention it. Yes, and today, out of those, I'll show you the official Hololive Production shop bonus!
こちら！じゃーん！
Here! Ta-da!
どうですか？これヤバくない？
How is it? Isn't this crazy?
え、なんと、えーっと、こちら、えー白押しのね、えー、こういう本当はね、こういう感じじゃないんだけど、ホロライブで予約すると、CDのデザインがこういう形になっております。いや、マジで綺麗。
Um, what's more, um, here, with silver foil stamping... normally it's not like this, but if you reserve it through Hololive, the CD design looks like this. Man, it's so pretty.
え、もうだからいろんなとこでゲットするのもあり。
Um, so getting it at various places is also an option.
え、ということで特典をちら見せしたところで、どんなアルバムになっているのか、えー少し紹介したいと思います。
So, having given a sneak peek at the bonuses, I'd like to introduce a bit about what kind of album it is.
えーこのアスターではトワのね、えーいろんなね、そのデビューしてからの今までとか、まいろんなこういうことがあってこんなことがあってこんな気持ちだよみたいな、いろんなのを詰め込んだアルバムになってまして、
In this "ASTER", it's an album packed with various things—from Towa's debut until now, like "various things happened, I felt this way"—all packed into it!
相談して、
After discussing it,
あの常闇トワが仕掛けましたって言って作られた曲なので
she had it made, saying, "Tokoyami Towa put this together!"
もう歌詞とか、
The lyrics and
あとMVもね
the music video...
このあとね、9時から公開するんですけれど
will be released tonight at 9:00 PM,
トワのチャンネルで公開するんですけれども
premiering right here on Towa's channel!
気合もね、入ってて、あの、素敵なMVとなっておりますので、ぜひ
She poured her heart into it, resulting in an amazing music video, so please—
よろしくお願いします！
please check it out!
そして、24時からね、各配信サイトで聴くことができるので
And starting at midnight, you can stream it on various music platforms,
えー、寝るも惜しんで、寝ないでください！
so please don't sleep—sacrifice your sleep!
寝ないで全部聞いてください、ずっと一緒ねとか言って
Listen to the whole thing without sleeping, like "We're together forever, right?"
ははは！とか言って
Haha! she says.
やばい、これね、あのね、意外と静かなのよ、トワは。
Oh no, surprisingly, Towa is pretty quiet about this.
えっとね、はい！
Um, right!
えー、じゃあ、寝ないで聞いてくださーい！
So, please listen to it without sleeping!
はーい！はずかしい。
Yeah! So embarrassing.
そして、そして、え、重大発表はアルバムだけではございません！
And now, our major announcement isn't just about the album!
トワとは、ソロライブ開催決定ーー！
Towa's... 1st solo live has been decided!
やー！もうトワね、えー、みんなが、トワ様ソロライブいつなの？
Yay! Everyone's been asking, "Towa-sama, when is your solo live?"
トワもやりたいんだよ！トワ様ソロライブ行きたいよ！トワもやりたいんだよ！
"I want to do it! I want to go to Towa-sama's solo live! I want to do it!"
そんなことを何回も繰り返しておりました。
I've repeated that so many times.
来ましたよ、みんな！
It's finally here, everyone!
みんなマジで来た！えー、常闇トワ1stソロライブ「Break your xxx」が、2023年10月13日立川ステージガーデンで開催されます！
Everyone, it's really happening! Tokoyami Towa's 1st solo live "Break your xxx" will be held on October 13, 2023, at Tachikawa Stage Garden!
えー、これね、Xじゃなくてバツなんです。
Now, this isn't an "X," it's a cross ("batsu").
で、このバツに何が入るかはみんなの方で考えてください。
Think about what fits into that cross yourselves.
壊したいものを越えたいもの、自分の殻を破りたいとか、
Things you want to break through, things you want to overcome, breaking out of your shell,
山を越えたいとか、壁をぶっ壊して頑張りたいみたいな、
crossing mountains, breaking down walls to work hard—
そういう時、そういう感じで自分の様々なものを壊すっていう意味になってますので、自分の考えてるもの当てはめてくれたら嬉しいなと思います。
it means breaking through various barriers and limitations in your own life, so I'd be happy if you apply it to your own thoughts.
えー、そしてアルバム『Aster』をメインとしてね、このソロライブをやります。
And we'll be performing this solo live centered around the album *Aster*.
そしてこのね、ソロライブなんですけれども、生バンド！すべて生バンドでやらせていただきます。
Also, for this solo live, it will be with a live band! Everything will be performed with a live band.
ライブもアルバムも、アルバムのハッシュタグは
Both the live and the album... the hashtag for the album is—
「#常闇トワ1stソロライブ」でつぶやいてください！分かりやすいと思います、よろしくお願いします！
Please tweet with "#TokoyamiTowa1stSoloLive"! It should be easy to remember, so please use it!
え、バツバツバツはリアルだと思う？キスだと思う？ちょっとキスではないよ、さすかにね。
Ugh, "batsu, batsu, batsu"—do you think it's real? Or a kiss? Well, it's definitely not a kiss, obviously.
えー、現地会場のチケットはこのあと9時から、ホロライブファンクラブ公式の先行がスタートします！
Venue tickets will start their official Hololive Fan Club advance sales tonight at 9:00 PM!
え、1階はスタンディング席、2、3階が指定席となっておりまして、それが販売されます。
Floor 1 will be standing seats, and Floors 2 and 3 will be reserved seats going on sale.
受付期間は8月6日までで抽選形式なので慌てらず申し込んでください。
The application period runs until August 6th, and it's a lottery format, so please apply without rushing.
また現地には来れないよという人のために有料配信もあります！プラットフォームはZ-aNで、こちらもチケット9時から販売開始です！
Also, for those who can't make it to the venue, paid streaming is available! The platform is Z-aN, and tickets also go on sale at 9:00 PM!
ライブ終了後11月13日までアーカイブが見放題！
You can watch the archive as much as you like until November 13th after the live ends!
申し込みは概要欄のホームページやホロライブプロダクションのTwitterをチェックしてみてください！マネちゃんが更新してくれるんじゃないかなと思います。
Check the homepage in the description and Hololive Production's Twitter for application details! I think management will update us.
はい、そして次はお待ちかねのライブといえばグッズが必要でしょ？はい、どうぞ！
Yes, and next is everyone's long-awaited... when it comes to live shows, you need goods, right? Here you go!
ライブのグッズ紹介になります！い、ライブのね定番アイテムがセットで登場！この応援セットを購入すると特典でリストバンドがついてきます！
This is the introduction of the live goods! The classic live items appear as a set! If you purchase this support set, you get a bonus wristband!
すごい可愛いかったよ！リストバンドでタオルを束ねて使ってみてください、右下にあります。
It's super cute! Try bundling your towel with the wristband—it's shown on the bottom right.
え、応援セットのグッズは個別に買うこともできますのでよろしくお願いします！
You can also purchase the support set goods individually, so please check them out!
では次！
Next up!
これ、バラバラのかな？Tシャツとペンライトとマフラータオルで、ちょっとかっこいめのものにしてみました！
These might be separate items? T-shirt, penlight, and muffler towel—we went for a cooler style this time!
え、これはねライブを応援する必須アイテムなんじゃないかなと思うのでぜひチェックお願いします！
I think these are essential items for supporting the live, so please be sure to check them out!
で、ここからは、あ、ここまでが先行先行、ごめんごめん、ここが先行発送グッズなので気をつけてくださいね！
And from here—ah, up to here are the advance shipping goods, so please be careful!
はい、そして次は受注販売するグッズです！これから紹介するアイテムはライブ後のお届けになるので注意してください！言いましたよ！
Next are the made-to-order goods! The items I'm introducing now will be delivered after the live, so please be careful! I told you!
はい、ロゴキーホルダーとキーケースとトートバッグです。
Yes, logo keyholder, key case, and tote bag.
ロゴキーホルダーはね、そう、今回のキービジュアルのイラストが入ってるものになっておりまして、キーケースはねちょっとかっこいめのレザー風仕様のものになっております。
The logo keyholder features the illustration from the key visual this time, and the key case has a cool leather-style finish.
トートバッグはね結構普段使いしやすいんじゃないかなと思います。ライブの記念にぜひゲットしてみてください！
The tote bag looks pretty easy to use in daily life. Be sure to get one to commemorate the live!
そしてまだまだ次！こちら！缶バッチとステッカー、アクリルスタンド、タペストリーとなっております！
And still more next! This one! Can badge & sticker set, acrylic stand, and tapestry!
えーっとね、トワのね、あのデビューしたときからずっとファンアートを描いてくださっている、らいむ先生が、あの素敵なね、イラストを描いてくれましたので、こちらのイラストを作ったグッズとなっておりますので、あの…
Um, Rime-sensei, who has been drawing fan art for Towa ever since her debut, drew this wonderful illustration, so these goods are created from that illustration, so...
きっちりね、マジで買ってくださいていう
Make sure to buy it in advance, okay?
感じです。え、アクリルスタンド
The acrylic stand is
めっちゃいいよ。まあ見たけど
really good! I've seen it too.
すごい良いから
It's really good, so
ぜひよろしくお願いします。
I'm counting on you!
ということで、えー
So, um,
最後にね、購入時の注意事項をお伝えします。
lastly, I'll share the purchase precautions.
販売期間はこのあと9時から8月14日の6時までです。
The sales period is from 9 PM today until August 14th at 6 PM.
先行発送料グッズと受注販売グッズと先ほど紹介したファーストアルバムマスターのお届けタイミングは全部違います。それぞれ違います。
Please note that pre-ordered goods, general goods, and the 1st album "Aster" will all have different shipping timings, so please check each one.
また、ライブ先行発送の商品は、発送商品以外の商品と同じカードで、カード内で購入しちゃうと発送期間内での発送ができません。みんなこれマジで注意ね。え、固めてね、同じもので。
Also, for items shipped prior to the live, if you purchase other items in the same cart, your order cannot be shipped within the shipping period! Everyone, please be really careful about this. Make sure to buy them separately!
えー、例えばこのライブの受注グッズ、アルバムマスター、そしてこのライブのグッズ以外のグッズを一緒に入れちゃうと、ライブに間に合わなくなっちゃいますと。
For example, if you put this live's pre-order goods, the album "Aster", and goods other than this live's goods all together, you won't make it in time for the live!
まとめると、ま、先行発送をご希望の場合は、先行発送のグッズだけでのご購入をお願いしますということです。マジでいつものやつ。でももうこれ言ったからね。えー、責任を今追ってます。
To sum up, if you want pre-order shipping, please make sure to purchase pre-order shipping goods by themselves! Seriously, like always, but I'm telling you now, so...
販売サイトのね、注意事項をよく確認してください。
Please carefully check the purchase precautions on the official shop!
もうあの今言ったからあとは責任を今ね。
I've said it now, so I'm taking responsibility!
はい。また、一部グッズはね、在庫限りの販売となってますので、詳しくはおしゃれ販売サイトと公演特設サイトをご確認ください。
Also, some goods have limited stock, so please check the sales site and the official/special site for details.
どのね、えー、ライブグッズもね、え、Yagooさんとね、あの、とわとね、もうとわがほとんど全部決めたんですけど、
As for the live goods, Yagoo-san and Towa-san—well, Towa decided almost all of them,
え、こういうのがいいんじゃないか、こういうのがいいんじゃないかってステキにね、作ってくださったので、もうぜひみんなに手に取ってほしいなと思います。
but they wonderfully made them based on "Wouldn't it be nice if we had this?" so I really want everyone to get their hands on them!
はい、ということで、え、すごい駆け足になってしまったんですが、本当に
Yes, so it went by really fast, but truly,
本当にあの今日、今日このみんなに発表する日、そしてライブ当日もね、絶対またドキドキしてると思うんですけど、このドキドキを
truly, today—the day I'm announcing this to everyone—and the day of the live itself, I'm sure I'll be feeling nervous again,
ま、当日までにもっともっと頑張って、え、いいものにして、このドキドキを強さに変えられるように頑張っていきますので、よろしくお願いします。
but I'll work even harder towards the day of the live so I can turn that nervousness into excitement, so please look forward to it!
はい、ということで、今日はみんな本当にありがとう！
Yes! So everyone, thank you truly so much!
え、アルバムもライブも楽しみにしといてください。
Please look forward to both the album and the live!
ではみんな9時からいっぱい情報が更新されるよ、よろしくね。
Well then, lots of information will be updated starting at 9 PM, so please look forward to it!
ということで、みんな、バイバーイ！マジでありがとう！
So everyone, bye-bye! Truly, thank you so much!
バイバイバイバイ！
Bye, bye, bye, bye!
常世の闇に囚われたままで
Trapped in the eternal darkness,
奏でる悲鳴を
playing a mournful cry...
周りからみた私 ワタシがおもう私
The "me" seen from others, the "me" I imagine...
固定概念 世間体 自己暗示から
Fixed concepts, worldly views, from self-hypnosis,
もっと自由に もっと私らしくあるために
more freely, for the sake of being more "me"—
私を縛る、XXXを
Break the XXX that binds me!
壊せ
Break it!
楽しい言葉に追い払われて
Driven away by pleasant words,
うつむいたまま叫ぶ赤い花
hanging my head down, shouting out loud.
黒く燃える痛みが食材なら 分け合え出逢うよ
If the pain is just firewood, let's meet to warm ourselves.
ずっとこのまま
Let's stay just like this forever.